Inventory of the Hamid Shawkat collection, 1952-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Materials, 1957-1991 (Box 29-35)
  - A Word with the "Pretenders" of Power in the "Republican" Opposition in Iran: Is Democracy Feasible in Iran?, Cosroe Chaqueri, pamphlet, 1982 (Folder 34: 8)
    In Persian.
  - Yek nāmeh sar goshādeh beh Doktor Manuchehr Hezārkhanī, Cosroe Chaqueri, pamphlet, January 1982 (Folder 34: 9)
  - Zamīn-hā tarīkhī, sīyāsī, eghtesādī va ijtemā'ī, Mahmoud Rasegh, booklet, 1988 (Folder 34: 10)
  - Zan dar jomhurī islāmī, pamphlets, 1980-1981 (Folder 34: 11)
  - Zendegī āsar va fā'alīat-hāyeh V.I. Lenin,(Berlin: Siyākal Publishing), book, 1977 (Folder 34: 12)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1987-1989 (Folder 35: 1)
  - Miscellaneous booklets, 1972-1978 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Miscellaneous booklets, 1985-1994 (Folder 35: 3)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1978-1995 (Folder 35: 4)
- Clippings, 1965-1991 (Box 36)
  Arranged in alphabetical order by title of newspaper, then chronological order.
  - Asghar āghā, no. 605, newspaper, 9 June 1984 (Folder 36: 1)
  - Azaraksh, newspaper, 1976-October 1978 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Azarbāijan, newspaper, January 1977 (Folder 36: 3)
  - Bīrlīk, newspapers, December 1975, January-December 1977, June and October 1978 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Frankfurter Rundschau, newspaper, circa June 1967 (Folder 36: 5)
    Headlines relate to death of student Benno Ohnesorg at protest rally.
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, no. 90, 14 October 1979 (Folder 36: 6)
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, no. 94, 15 October 1979 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, nos. 29, 50, 64, 72, 76-77, 93, 98, 100 and 108, 1979 (Folder 36: 8)
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, no. 416, 1980 (Folder 36: 9)
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, no. 65, 25 January-5 February 1984 (Folder 36: 10)
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, no. 218, 28 August-10 September 1989 (Folder 36: 11)
  - Inqilāb-i islāmī, undated (Folder 36: 12)
    Headling of circled article: "Etlā'yeh sāzemān-i ittehād-i mobārzeh dar rāh-i āzādī tabaqeh kārgar".
  - Iran Times, newspaper, 4 August, 1989 (Folder 36: 13)
  - Junge Stimme, 25 September 1965 (Folder 36: 14)
  - Kayhān, newspapers and clippings, 1978-1979 (Folder 36: 15)
  - Kayhān (Airmail Edition), 28 December 1977-20 January 1988 (Folder 36: 16)
  - Khodā shāh, newspaper, 1 mordad 2548 (Folder 36: 17)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1979-1991 (Folder 36: 18)
  - Nedāī-yeh khalq, no. 3, newspaper, 1979 (Folder 36: 19)
  - Small clipping regarding Iranian protests, undated (Folder 36: 20)
  - Telegraf, no. 127/22, newspaper, 3 June 1967 (Folder 36: 21)
- Miscellany, 1965-1991 (Box 37-38)
  Printed materials, photograph, other writings, and photocopied research materials on Marxist theory.
  Files are arranged by format, then in chronological order.
  - Articles and Reports, 1968-1988 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous reports, 1977-1988 (Folder 37: 1-3)
    - Seminar report, June 1968 (Folder 37: 4)
  - Journals, 1974-1987 (Box 37)
    - Daf'ā az zendānīyān sīyāsī īrān, no. 1, 1965 (Folder 37: 5)
    - Hāl va ruzgār mohejarān-i afghānī dar īrān, undated (Folder 37: 6)
    - Journal about events of the Freedom Conference in Seattle featuring articles on the Commitee for Artistic and Intellectual Freedom in Iran, undated (Folder 37: 7)
    - Organ of the General Union of Afghani Students in Germany, 1978 (Folder 37: 8)
  - Newsletters and Bulletins, 1978-1991 (Box 37)
    - Barāyeh āzādī, 1978-1986 (Folder 37: 9)
    - Iranian Cultural Center, Frankfurt, 1988-1991 (Folder 37: 10)
  - Papers, 1970-1987 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970-1987 (Folder 37: 11)
  - Other media, photograph and brochures, undated (Box 37)
    - Brochure from Amnesty International, undated (Folder 37: 12)
      Includes information concerning the rights of political prisoners in Iran.
    - 1 photograph of professionally-dressed man, black and white, undated (Folder 37: 13)
    - Circulated postcard with "Respect Human Rights" printed in 5 languages, undated (Folder 37: 14)
      Addressed to Ayatollāh Khomeini.
  - Research Materials, circa 1971 (Box 38: 1-6)
    Includes photocopies of essays articles on Marxism and political theory, in Persian and English.